MIKE SCHRIEFER

DATA ANALYST



(732) 864-5047



mikeschriefer11@gmail.com



github.com/MikeSchriefer

PROFILE

A Data Analyst whose affinity for data stems from using range logs to predict shot placement in long range marksmanship. With strong leadership traits developed over 9+ years in the military, I am well adept at solving complex problems in a fast-paced environment.

SKILLS

- Python
- Tableau
- SQL
- Excel &
- Power BI
- **PowerPoint**

PROJECTS

Low Income and Elderly Assistance Project

 Worked with US Tax Return Data to determine which groups would be best suited for a grant. Utilized Excel for data cleaning/visualization

App Trader Project

 Used SQL to filter data from both Apple App Store and Google Play Store to choose which applications would best fit our client's criteria for purchasing. Presented findings with Microsoft Powerpoint

Powerlifting Dashboard

 Created an interactive dashboard with Tableau to compare results of drug tested and untested powerlifters from across world

NFL Player Arrests Dashboard

 Visualized the NFL player arrest data to explore trends and gain insights using Power BI

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics, expected graduation Jun 2020

• 3 month Data Analytics Bootcamp

US Army Ranger School

January 2016 - April 2016

• The US Army's premier combat leadership school

US Army Basic Leader's Course

June 2016 - August 2016

 Received the Audie Murphy Award for Outstanding Leadership

DATA ANALYTICS EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Data Analyst

March 2020 - present

- An immersive full-time data analytics program
- Worked with real-world datasets to develop hard skills in data cleaning, data exploration, and data visualization
- Experience working/collaborating in a 100% remote work environment

WORK EXPERIENCE

US Army

Section Leader

Jan 2015 - Jan 2020

- Supervised and led squad of 12 soldiers, setting high standard of efficiency, loyalty and integrity
- Conducted regular counseling of subordinate leadership, reviewing tasks month to month and setting new monthly professional and personal goals
- Maintained property and equipment inventory valued over \$250,000
- Led a 20-soldier detail tasked with range safety for live fire and maneuver range. My team successfully conducted the range, coordinating between up to three separate moving elements, resulting in 0 injuries or loss of equipment over 9 live iterations
- Developed a system for controlling traffic flow for 700+ military vehicles by creating an organized staging area and directing one vehicle at a time
- As a Ranger Instructor, provided clear, informative lectures for up to 40 students and evaluated performance over 24-hour long simulated operations, developed detailed reports, and provided extensive feedback
- Developed operational risk management worksheets to minimize danger to students in an intensive 20-day course while operating in field conditions

Dang Brother Pizza and Food Truck Fleet

Manager

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015

- Created and deployed successful strategies to boost performance, streamline processes and increase efficiency by creating a system to track inventory across multiple truck locations and the main supply point
- Applied knowledge of previous supply needs and forecasted business levels to estimate required supplies
- Organized special events from small private events to large-scale music festivals (Coachella) while managing day-to-day operations at permanent locations
- Experienced with personalized BEO's and ensuring each client received exceptional customer service and experience
- Built and managed personnel schedules for store, truck fleet and catering operations

US Marine Corps

Squad Leader

Aug 2009 - Sept 2013

- Managed, trained, and developed squad of 7, supervised more than \$200,000 in high-value equipment maintaining zero loss record over 4 years, including 2 deployments
- Advised senior leaders on emplacement of weapon systems in various real-world tactical scenarios